Register of the Paul Robert Hanna Papers, 1920-1997
Hoover Institution Archives
- INCREMENT OF MARCH 1985
  - SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1928-1979
    - "What Thrwarts the Community School Curriculum," article, Community Education Journal, May 1972. (Folder 168: 5)
    - Bangladesh Emergency Relief Fund, brochure, 1972 (Folder 168: 6)
    - East-West Center, American Alumni Directory, 1972 (Folder 168: 7)
    - Stanford Inner Quad, 1972/73 (Folder 168: 8)
    - Stiles, Lindley J., "Policy and Perspective," The Journal of Educational Research, November 1973 (Folder 168: 9)
    - On the Campus, Maui Community College, Hawaii, 1973 (Folder 168: 10)
    - Stanford University endowed professorships, 1973 (Folder 168: 11)
    - Twight, Peter A., "Ecological Forestry for the Coast Redwoods,", 1973 (Folder 168: 12)
    - "Educational Exchange in the Pacific Community," speech, World Campus Afloat, January 1974. (Folder 168: 13)
    - Gill, Martin, "Paul R. Hanna: The Evolution of an Elementary Social Studies Textbook Series," dissertation, Northwestern University, August 1974 (Folder 168: 14)
    - Blair, A. K., "Spelling," Education, 1974 (Folder 168: 15)
    - On the Campus, San Francisco State University, 1974 (Folder 168: 16)
    - Letter to the editor, The National Elementary Principal, January/February 1975. (Folder 168: 17)
    - "Introducing the Association & an Invitation to Join," article, The Imprint of the Stanford Libraries Associates, April 1975. (Folder 168: 18)
    - Financial Planner, Hamline University, Summer 1975 (Folder 168: 18A)
    - Castilleja Bulletin, Winter 1975 (Folder 168: 19)
    - "The Care and Feeding of Spaceship Earth,", 1975. (Folder 168: 20)
    - Hamline University Annual Report, 1975-76 (Folder 168: 21)
    - Stanford University Libraries Annual Report, 1975-76 (Folder 168: 22)
    - Peninsula Life, January 1976 (Folder 168: 23)
    - Pearce Mitchell Condominiums dedication, clippings and texts of speeches, April 30, 1976 (Folder 168: 24)
    - "Coping With Interdependence," report, International Educational and Cultural Exchange, Spring 1976. (Folder 168: 25)
    - Peace Corps Bi-annual Statistical Summary, June 30, 1976 (Folder 168: 26)
    - Hamline University Bulletin, 1976
      - July (Box-folder 169: 1)
      - October (Folder 169: 2)
    - Inner Quad Annual Report, 1976-77 (Folder 169: 3)
      Stanford University
    - "The Instructional Dilemma Today - One Educator's Perspective," speech, California County Superintendents of Schools and Staffs Convention, January 20, 1977. (Folder 169: 4)
    - "Hanna Blasts Chaos in Curriculum of Public Schools," article, Campus Report, Stanford University, February 9, 1977. (Folder 169: 5)
    - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, Report, 1977 (Folder 169: 6)
    - Commencement Address at Hamline University, May 20, 1979. (Folder 169: 7)
    - Air Affairs, 1946-1950
      - "Education for an Air World,", December 1946. (Folder 169: 8)
      - "Education and Air Affairs: The Next Issue,", Autumn 1947 (Folder 169: 9)
      - Introduction, Winter 1948. (Folder 169: 10)
      - Autumn 1949 (Folder 169: 11)
      - Spring 1950 (Folder 169: 12)
    - National Curriculum Commission, 1956-1963
      - NEA 97th Annual Meeting, St. Louis, June 28-July 3, 1956 (Box-folder 170: 1)
      - "Social Studies for Today," article, NEA Journal, January 1959. (Folder 170: 2)
        Reprint.
      - "Proposed – A National Commission for Curriculum Research and Development," article, Phi Delta Kappan, May 1961. (Folder 170: 3)
      - "A National Commission for Curriculum Research and Development,", 1961. (Folder 170: 4)
      - "Curriculum and Instruction - A Proposal Concerning the NEA's Future Role in These Areas," article, NEA Journal, January 1963. (Folder 170: 5)
  - Printed matter (Folder 170: 6)
  - Visual-aids (Folder 170: 7)
- INCREMENT OF SEPTEMBER 1985
  - Speeches and writings, 1933-1963
    - "Education As an Instrument of National Policy in Selected Newly Developing Nations," with Donald M. Foster, 1963. (Box-folder 171: 1)
    - "Readings in Methods of Social Change,", n.d. (Folder 171: 2)
    - "The Role of Education in Utilizing Regional Resources - A Preliminary Report," The Progressive Education Association, 1939. (Folder 171: 3)
    - "Spelling (Encoding)," Michigan Department of Education (Folder 171: 4)
    - Tentative Course of Study for the Core Curriculum of Secondary Schools, Virginia, State Board of Education, Bulletin, Richmond, 1933. (Box-folder 172: 1)
  - Subject file, 1947-1982
    - Channon, Gloria, "Speling - As an Aid to Reading,", January 1969 (Folder 172: 2)
    - Consultant contracts, 1968-69 (Folder 172: 3)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1978 (Folder 172: 4)
    - Gazos Creek Farms
      - 1979 (Folder 172: 5)
      - 1980 (Folder 172: 6)
      - General (Folder 172: 7)
      - Bills, 1979-1982 (Folder 172: 8)
      - Cancelled checks and statements, 1979 (Folder 172: 9)
      - Checkbook stubs, 1977-1981 (Folder 172: 10)
      - Claim against San Mateo County, inverse condemnation, 1974-75 (Folder 172: 11)
      - Correspondence, 1977-79 (Box-folder 173: 1)
      - Gifts to children (Folder 173: 2)
      - Grieg: TSI/1981 (Folder 173: 3)
      - Hanna's record of supervision time spent (Folder 173: 4)
      - Harvest plans and permits
        - Contract for timber sale, Big Creek #1 & 4, 1977 (Folder 173: 5)
        - Contract for timber sale, Harwood #1, 3, 5, 1978 (Folder 173: 6)
        - Contracts for timber sale, Philo #5, 1979 (Folder 173: 7)
        - Forest Improvement Program, 1980 (Folder 173: 8)
        - Forest Incentive Program and Agricultural Conservation Program (Folder 173: 9)
        - Forest Practice Inspection Reports, 1975-79 (Folder 173: 10)
        - Guthmillers 0.9 Acres (Folder 173: 11)
        - State and county, 1979 (Folder 173: 12)
        - Timber harvest plans and permit, state and county, 1978 (Folder 173: 13)
        - Timber sales, 1978 (Folder 173: 14)
      - Logging (Folder 173: 15)
      - Logging contracts and products reports (Folder 173: 16)
      - Nature Conservancy (Folder 173: 17)
      - Permits to use for recreation (Folder 173: 18)
      - Possible buyers
        - Barbeque, 1981 (Folder 173: 19)
          guests
        - Bushnell/Herrick (Box-folder 174: 1)
        - Harwood Products (Folder 174: 2)
        - Inquiries and offers rejected (Folder 174: 3)
        - Louisiana Pacific Corporation (Folder 174: 4)
        - Passmore, Leslie G. (LP Land & Timber Co.) (Folder 174: 5)
        - Santa Cruz Lumber Co. (Folder 174: 6)
        - Stone brothers, Ernest Locatelli, Tom Sampson (Folder 174: 7)
        - Tan, Shu (Folder 174: 8)
        - Tuemmler/Whitney (Folder 174: 9)
        - Weldon Girard Realty (Folder 174: 10)
        - Miscellaneous (Folder 174: 11)
      - Redwood Workshop stump sale (Folder 174: 12)
      - Sale distribution (Folder 174: 13)
      - Sale inquiries (Folder 174: 14)
      - Sempervirens Fund (Folder 174: 15)
      - State Department of Parks and Recreation (Folder 174: 16)
      - Talk on Gazos Creek for Stanford Historical Society, October 6, 1981 (Folder 174: 17)
      - Taxes
        - 1955-1981
          - Tree Farm #1 (Folder 174: 18)
          - Tree Farm #2 (Box-folder 175: 1)
        - 1977 (Folder 175: 2)
        - California State Yield Tax, 1973-79 (Folder 175: 3)
        - Federal, Capital Gains, Inheritance (Folder 175: 4)
        - Tree Farm #4, 1959-1981 (Folder 175: 5)
        - Tree Farm #5, 1972-1981 (Folder 175: 6)
      - Title insurance (Folder 175: 7)
      - Tree Farming 1972 Award (Folder 175: 8)
      - Values (Folder 175: 9)
    - Hillerich, Robert L., "Let's Teach Spelling - Not Phonetic Misspelling,", March 1977 (Folder 175: 10)
    - Henderson, Adin D., "The Life of Ellwood Patterson Cubberley,", September 1952 (Folder 175: 11)
    - Hopper, J. Victor, "Contributions to Education By Dr. Ellwood Patterson Cubberley,", October 1947 (Box-folder 176: 1)
    - Hotson, Clarence, "Riht Ryting for Spelling Reform,", 1968 (Folder 176: 2)
    - Individual Income Tax Return, 1974 (Folder 176: 3)
    - Jelinek, August and Frederic Tonge, "Forecasts of California Teacher Supply and Demand, 1945-1960," (Folder 176: 4)
    - Membership cards (Folder 176: 5)
    - Michigan, Department of Education, Curriculum Division
      - "Language Skills Programs - Spelling: Encoding,", 1969 (Folder 176: 6)
      - Worksheets, n.d. (Folder 176: 7)
    - Mountain Camp (Folder 176: 8)
    - Passports (Folder 176: 9)
    - Philanthropy
      - Castilleja (Folder 176: 10)
      - Gifts and fund raising (Folder 176: 11)
      - Hamline University (Box-folder 177: 1-3)
      - Palo Alto Medical Foundation (Folder 177: 4)
      - Summary (Folder 177: 5)
    - Resnikoff, H. L. and J. L. Dolby
      - "The Nature of Affixing in Written English,", July 1964 (Folder 177: 6)
      - "The Role of Hyphenation in the Composition of Printed Text,", July 1964 (Folder 177: 7)
    - Securities and income record, 1974-77 (Folder 177: 8)
    - The Sequoias (Folder 177: 9)
    - Smelt, Elsie D., "Teaching The Language As It Is,", 1977 (Folder 177: 10)
    - Speaking engagements, 1973 (Folder 177: 11)
    - Stanford University
      - "Endowed Professorships at Stanford University,", 1979 (Folder 177: 12)
      - Retirement (Folder 177: 13)
      - School of Education, long-range academic planning, 1976-78 (Box-folder 178: 1-2)
    - Watts, Noel, "George Hogben,", n.d. (Folder 178: 3)
  - Printed matter (Box 179-180)
  - World Book Encyclopedia, 1966 (Reading room Reading Room)
    19 volumes
- INCREMENT OF NOVEMBER 1985
  - Ahlstrom, Karl-Georg, "Studies in Spelling, IV, Developmental Changes With Age in Tests Measuring Knowledge of Pronounciation and Spelling Rules,"., 1967 (Box-folder 181: 1)
  - Appointment books
    - 1928-1971
    - 1957
      - June 24 - September 22 (Box-folder 182: 1)
      - September 23 - December 30 (Folder 182: 2)
    - 1958
      - January 1 - March 1 (Folder 182: 3)
      - March 31 - June 23 (Folder 182: 4)
      - June 23 – September 29 (Folder 182: 5)
      - September 29 - December 31 (Folder 182: 6)
    - 1959
      - January 1 - March 31 (Box-folder 183: 1)
      - March 30 - June 30 (Folder 183: 2)
      - June 22 - September 30 (Folder 183: 3)
      - September 28 - December 31 (Folder 183: 4)
    - 1960
      - January 1 - March 31 (Folder 183: 5)
      - March 28 - June 30 (Folder 183: 6)
      - June 20 - September 25 (Box-folder 184: 1)
      - September 26 - December 16 (Folder 184: 2)
    - 1961
      - January 3 - March 24 (Folder 184: 3)
      - April – June (Folder 184: 4)
      - June 26 - September 5 (Folder 184: 5)
      - September 25 - December 15 (Folder 184: 6)
    - 1962
      - January 3 - March 23 (Box-folder 185: 1)
      - April 2 - June 17 (Folder 185: 2)
      - June 25 - September 4 (Folder 185: 3)
      - September 25 - December 14 (Folder 185: 4)
    - 1963
      - January 7 - March 22 (Folder 185: 5)
      - April 1 - June 12 (Folder 185: 6)
      - June 24 - August 17 (Box-folder 186: 1)
      - September 23 - December 13 (Folder 186: 2)
    - 1964
      - January 6 - March 20 (Folder 186: 3)
      - March 30 - June 10 (Folder 186: 4)
      - June 22 - August 15 (Folder 186: 5)
      - September 28 - December 18 (Folder 186: 6)
    - 1965
      - 1965 January 1 - March 28 (Box-folder 187: 1)
      - March 29 - June 20 (Folder 187: 2)
      - September 27 - January 2 (1966) (Folder 187: 3)
    - 1966
      - January 3 - March 27 (Folder 187: 4)
      - March 28 - June 11 (Folder 187: 5)
      - June 20 - August 13 (Folder 187: 6)
      - September 26 - December 16 (Box-folder 188: 1)
    - 1967
      - Various months (Folder 188: 2)
      - January – December (Folder 188: 3)
      - January – March (Folder 188: 4)
      - April - June (Folder 188: 5)
      - June - August (Folder 188: 6)
      - September - December (Box-folder 189: 1)
    - 1968
      - January – March (Folder 189: 2)
      - April - June (Folder 189: 3)
      - June - August (Folder 189: 4)
      - September - December (Folder 189: 5)
    - 1969
      - January - April (Folder 189: 6)
      - April - June (Box-folder 190: 1)
      - June - September (Folder 190: 2)
      - October - December (Folder 190: 3)
    - 1970
      - January - March (Folder 190: 4)
      - April - June (Folder 190: 5)
      - July - September (Folder 190: 6)
      - October - December (Box-folder 191: 1)
    - 1971
      - January - March (Folder 191: 2)
      - March - June (Folder 191: 3)
      - July - September (Folder 191: 4)
      - October - December (Folder 191: 5)
  - Bezanson, Keith A., "A Tribute to Professor Paul R. Hanna,", Fall 1967 (Folder 191: 6)
  - Biographical file
    - 1966 (Folder 191: 7)
    - 1967-68 (Folder 191: 8)
    - General (Folder 191: 9)
    - California State Committee on Public Education, consultant to, 1966 (Box-folder 192: 1)
    - Philippine award, 1958 (Folder 192: 2)
    - Report of activities, 1968 (Folder 192: 3)
    - Salary, 1961-63 (Folder 192: 4)
    - Stanford University faculty record, 1953 (Folder 192: 5)
    - Summary of activities for Stanford University President's Annual Report
      - 1938-1959 (Folder 192: 6)
      - 1959-1967 (Folder 192: 7)
    - Teaching schedules, course listings, 1960-65 (Folder 192: 8)
    - Travelling expenses, 1961-66 (Folder 192: 9)
    - Who's Who in America, 1941 (Folder 192: 10)
  - Columbia University
    - Barnard College, study of income and expenditure in professional group, 1933 (Folder 192: 11)
    - Lincoln School of Teachers, promotional material, 1932-33
      - "A Brief Description of Two Units of Work On Indian Life and the Dutch Colonial Settlement" (Folder 192: 12)
      - "Brief Description of Two Units of Work With Some Underlying Theory" (Folder 192: 13)
      - Chapters III-V (Folder 192: 14)
      - Curriculum material (Folder 192: 15)
      - Initiating units of work (Folder 192: 16)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1983
    - 1968 (Box-folder 193: 1)
    - Air Affairs, 1949 (Folder 193: 2)
    - Andrus, J. Russell, 1957 (Folder 193: 3)
    - Arnett, Dixon (re: California Coastal Zone Conservation Commission), 1976 (Folder 193: 4)
    - Bowden, A. O., 1942 (Folder 193: 5)
    - Dutton, W. H., 1958 (Folder 193: 6)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica Films, Inc., 1947 (Folder 193: 7)
    - Eurich, Alvin, 1944 (Folder 193: 8)
    - Fejos, Paul (The Viking Fund, Inc.), 1942 (Folder 193: 9)
    - Giesecke, Albert A., 1941-42 (Folder 193: 10)
    - Lynch, John E., 1967 (Folder 193: 11)
    - Myers, Noel T., 1958 (Folder 193: 12)
    - Nilan, Roxanne, 1983 (Folder 193: 13)
    - Partridge, William D., 1959 (Folder 193: 14)
    - Sterling, J. E. Wallace, 1966 (Folder 193: 15)
    - Summers, Paul D. (Folder 193: 16)
    - Tresidder, Donald B., 1943-47 (Folder 193: 17)
    - U.S. Information Agency, 1966-68 (Folder 193: 18)
  - Cosmos Club, 1969-1977 (Folder 193: 19)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica Films, catalogs (Folder 193: 20)
  - Field Enterprises (World Book Encyclopedia)
    - 1950-55 (Folder 193: 21)
    - 1956-57 (Folder 193: 22)
    - 1957-1965 (Box-folder 194: 1)
    - Author specification sheets (Folder 194: 2)
  - Forestry conservation and San Mateo County Coastside Development (Folder 194: 3)
  - "Growth Management - Practices and Issues," a report prepared for the Assembly Committee on Local Government, San Diego, February 1975 (Folder 194: 4)
  - Harvard University, summer sessions, 1958-59 (Folder 194: 5)
  - Kellogg Foundation, 1948 (Folder 194: 6)
  - Learning, methods of (Folder 194: 7-9)
  - MacLean, Malcolm S.
    - "Adventures in Occupied Areas,", July 1975 (Box-folder 195: 1)
    - "Never a Dull Moment,", May 1977 (Folder 195: 2)
  - Mekong Project (Folder 195: 3)
  - Mutual Security Agency, Washington, D.C., 1952-53 (Folder 195: 4)
  - National Association of Elementary School Principals, meeting, April 18-21, 1970 (Folder 195: 5)
  - Philippines - UNESCO, 1948-49 (Folder 195: 6)
  - Preston, Ralph, "Childrens Reactions to Harsh Social Realities,", n.d. (Folder 195: 7)
  - Reading (Folder 195: 8)
  - San Francisco Bay Region Environment and Resources Planning Study, 1972
    - Earthquakes (Folder 195: 9)
    - Geologic map (Folder 195: 10)
    - Lanslide susceptibility (Folder 195: 11)
  - Santa Barbara
    - City schools, "Developmental Curriculum" (Folder 195: 12)
    - County Growth Chart, December 1944 (Folder 195: 13)
  - Scott, Foresman and Company
    - Investigating Man's World, Inter-American Studies
      - Canada, (1970-71) (Box-folder 196: 1)
      - Latin American Studies, (1970-71) (Folder 196: 2)
      - Mexico, (1970-71) (Folder 196: 3)
    - Investigating Man's World, Regional Studies
      - Anthropology, (1970) (Folder 196: 4)
      - Economics, (1970) (Folder 196: 5)
      - Geography, (1970) (Folder 196: 6)
      - History, (1970) (Folder 196: 7)
      - Political Science, (1970) (Folder 196: 8)
      - Sociology, (1970) (Folder 196: 9)
    - Investigating Man's Worlds United States Studies
      - Anthropology, (1970-71) (Folder 196: 10)
      - Economics, (1970-71) (Folder 196: 11)
      - Geography, (1970-71) (Folder 196: 12)
      - History, (1970-71) (Folder 196: 13)
      - Political Science, (1971) (Folder 196: 14)
      - Sociology, (1970-71) (Folder 196: 15)
    - Teacher's Key for Beyond the Americas, 1965 (Folder 196: 16-18)
    - Tests for In All Our States, In the Americas, and Beyond the Americas (Box-folder 197: 1-7)
  - Shift of civilization chart (Box-folder 198: 1)
  - Solomon, Herbert and Ian MacNeill, "Spelling Ability: A Comparison Between Computer Output Based on a Phoneme-Graphemic Algorithm and Actual Student Performance in Elementary Grades,", June 1966 (Folder 198: 2)
  - Speeches and writings
    - General (Folder 192: 3)
    - Beirut, Lebanon, notes on, May 10, 1963. (Folder 198: 4)
    - "Constructive Experimentation in Elementary Schools,", n.d. (Folder 198: 5)
    - "Conventional and Unconventional Education for Newly Developed Countries,", 1962. (Folder 198: 6)
    - "Educating Men For Economic Productivity," speech, July 18, 1955. (Folder 198: 7)
    - "Education: Instrument of National Policy,", n.d. (Folder 198: 8)
    - "Is the Traditional Concept of Local Control of Public Education Still Valid?" speech, AASA Convention, February 17-21, 1962. (Folder 198: 9)
    - "Memo to Myself," regarding St. Paul's Cathedral in London, May 26, 1978. (Folder 198: 10)
    - "The NEA's Role in Curriculum and Instruction," speech, Denver, July 5, 1962. (Folder 198: 11)
    - "Philippine Educators Show the Way,", 1955. (Folder 198: 12)
    - "Readings in Methods of Social Change,", n.d. (Folder 198: 13)
    - Report on tour of duty in four African nations, November 27, 1967. (Folder 198: 14)
    - "Resolved: That a National Commission for Curriculum Research and Development is Desirable," (Folder 198: 15)
    - "The Satellite and the Emerging Inter-American Community,", July 1968. (Folder 198: 16)
    - "The Structure and Style of Education in the United States: A Comparative Analysis,", October 24, 1966. (Folder 198: 17)
    - "The Teaching of Spelling," with Jean Hanna, n.d. (Folder 198: 18)
  - Spelling (Folder 198: 19)
  - Stanford University
    - General (Folder 198: 20)
    - Academic Council
      - Advisory Board, 1964-67 (Folder 198: 21)
      - Ballots, 1962-64 (Folder 198: 22)
      - Executive Committee, 1964 (Folder 198: 23)
    - School of Education
      - General (Box-folder 199: 1)
      - Comparative Education Center
        - "Education As An Instrument of National Policy in Selected Newly Developing Nations,", 1963 (Folder 199: 2-3)
      - Comparative (overseas) education (Folder 199: 4)
      - Dissertations
        - Andrews, Clay S., "Social Science Generalizations for Use in the Social Studies Curriculum,", May 1957 (Folder 199: 5)
        - Bradford, Henry F., "Oral-Aural Differentiation Among Phonemes As a Factor in Spelling Readiness,", August 1952 (Folder 199: 6)
        - Davies, Gordon F., "Map Skills and Understandings in Intermediate School Social Studies,", March 1962 (Box-folder 200: 1)
        - Del Rosso, Joseph, "Structured Social Studies Content for Elementary Schools, June 1967 (Folder 200: 2)
        - Douglass, Malcolm P., "Interrelationships Between Man and the Natural Environment For Use in the Geographic Strand of the Social Studies Curriculum,", 1954 (Folder 200: 3)
        - Emmerson, Harold G., "Social Science Generalizations for Use in the Social Studies Curriculum,", May 1957 (Box-folder 201: 1)
        - Frasier, Vance C, "Regular Phonetic Spellings Appearing in a Three Thousand Word Vocabulary,", August 1951 (Folder 201: 2)
        - Freeman, Harold, "The Role of Agricultural Education in the Economic Development of Thailand,", December 1964 (Folder 201: 3)
        - Geer, Owen C, "Social Science Generalizations for Use in the Social Studies Curriculum,", December 1958 (Folder 201: 4)
        - Hebler, Jane A., "Structured Social Studies Content for Elementary Schools,", August 1965 (Folder 201: 5)
        - Hofstrand, John M., "Social Science Generalizations for Use in the Social Studies Curriculum,", September 1969 (Box-folder 202: 1)
        - LaMarche, Alfred, "Structured Social Studies Content for Elementary Schools,", June 1967 (Folder 202: 2)
        - Lee, John R., "Social Science Generalizations for Use in the Social Science Curriculum,", August 1957 (Folder 202: 3)
        - Miller, Norman A., "Structured Social Studies Content for Elementary Schools,", June 1967 (Folder 202: 4)
        - Moore, James T., "Phonetic Elements Appearing in a Three Thousand Word Vocabulary,", June 1951 (Box-folder 203: 1)
        - Parker, Weldon R., "Structured Social Studies Content for Elementary Schools,", August 1964 (Folder 203: 2)
        - Peck, Albert D., "Social Science Generalizations for Use in the Social Studies Curriculum,", January 1958 (Folder 203: 3)
        - Rambeau, John F., "Social Science Generalizations for Use in the Social Studies Curriculum,", October 1956 (Folder 203: 4)
        - Rea, Thelma M., "Discipline in Oral-Aural Discrimination As a Factor in Developing Power in Spelling,", June 1958 (Box-folder 204: 1)
        - Runge, James R., "Social Science Generalizations for Use in the Social Studies Curriculum,", May 1958 (Folder 204: 2)
        - Rusteika, George P., "Social Science Generalizations for Use in the Social Studies Curriculum,", May 1958 (Folder 204: 3)
        - Stratton, Vinton, "Social Science Generalizations for Use in the Social Studies,", April 1957 (Folder 204: 4)
        - White, Harry R., "Possible Effects of Selected Educational Policies and Programs... ,", December 1964 (Folder 204: 5)
        - Williams, Forbes W., "Structured Social Studies Content for Elementary Schools,", July 1965 (Box-folder 205: 1)
      - "Phoneme-Grapheme Correspondences as Cues to Spelling Improvement," U.S.O.E. Research Project No. 1991, 1965 (Folder 205: 2-3)
      - Stanford International Development Education Center (SIDEC)
        - Baty, Roger M., "The Effect of Cross-Cultural Inservice Training on Selected Attitudes of Elementary School Teacher Volunteers,", October 1970 (Folder 205: 4)
        - "Content and Instructional Methods of Education for the Economic-Political-Social Development of Nations,", April 1971 (Folder 205: 5)
        - Foley, Douglas E., "Culture, Politics, and Schools in Rural Philippines,", 1971 (Folder 205: 6)
        - Satorn, Pinyo, "The Provincial School Superintendent in Thailand,", 1971 (Folder 205: 7)
        - Sims, Dennis C, "Self-image and Social Change Towards an Integrated Theory of Cybernetic Behaviour,", 1971 (Box-folder 206: 1)
        - Summary of Research on Education and the Rural-Urban Transformation, Final Report, September 1970 (Folder 206: 2)